Mss.B.J35
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Messrs. Havens & Dering, Dec. 22, 1791; B J35.45; 9 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges information on the Hessian fly. Interest of APS in subject. Bur. of rolls, S.1,4,243.
  - Letter to David Rittenhouse, Philadelphia, Aug. 12, 1792; B J35.63; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L. 1p.and add. Signature clipped. Instructions for purchasing "Equatorial" instrument from Mr. Leiper.
  - Letter to [David] Rittenhouse, dated Philadelphia, Apr. 11, 1793; B J35.1; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    pertains to instructions which the [American philosophical] Society is to frame for Michaud [André Michaux's journey to the western country]. A.L.S. 1p. and address. See Early Minutes - meetings for April 19 and 30, 1793 (A.P.S. Proceedings, v.22, pt.3) Purchased for the Society by Arthur Pforzheimer [New York bookdealer] at the Parke-Burnet sale held on March 10,1938, #66.- Has been microfilmed - see Film No. 71; see also Film 199, 81
  - Letter to David Rittenhouse, Philadelphia, Nov. 6, 1793; B J35.64; 10x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Sends bill of lading for copper for the mint. Asks if new engraver is needed for the mint.
  - Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives of the U.S., December 16, 1793; B J35.6; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Philadelphia, Encloses his report, as Secretary of State on the privileges and restrictions on the commerce of the United States in foreign countries. Copy of L. and D. 22p. 0. Contains also the action of the Committee of the House upon the Report. For printed copy of letter and report see Bergh - Writings of Thomas Jefferson, V.3,261; Ford - Writings of Thomas Jefferson, V.6,470. See also Bureau of Rolls, Bulletin, V.6,221 (Calendar of Jefferson Papers). Not Found: 7/19/2010
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin Bache, Philadelphia, Dec. 26, 1795; B J35.56; 9x7-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Jefferson papers.) Order for his newspaper. Wishes to know of new edition of Benjamin Franklin's works. From original in Central Library, Salford, England.
  - Letter to Bushrod Washington, Oct. 9, 1796; B J35.24; 7" x 9"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Encloses record in the case of Dickerson v. Paulett & Marks.
  - Letter to [Thomas] Willing, Feb. 23, 1798; B J35.72; 5x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. (Francis Lewis Randolph Collection of Thomas Jefferson materials) Gives reason why he never attends evening parties, and cannot attend the Assembly. Never attended Washington's parties.
  - Letter to Samuel Smith, Aug. 22, 1798; B J35.11; 7 1/2" x 9"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 4p. Printed: Lipscomb and Bergh, v.10, 55.
  - Letter to Genl. Daniel Smith, Sep.10, 1800; B J35.36; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges Chickasaw vocabulary; anxious to preserve as many Indian languages as possible. News of friends.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], August 22, 1800; B J35.x1; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 5p. From original in Library of Congress; presented by Col. Lawrence Martin, April 1944.
  - Letter to Benjamin Rush, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1800; B J35.12; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. Concerning yellow fever, the XYZ affair, religion, and Franklin.
  - Letter to Benjamin Rush, Dec. 14, 1800; B J35.8; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges melon seeds. Republicans seem to have obtained a majority of 8 in the late election. Bureau of Rolls, V.6,398-S.2,v.70,52.
  - Letter to Dwight Foster, Feb. 1, 1802; B J35.32; 8" x 5"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. and add., end. Invitation to dine. (Came originally with Jenks-Jefferson collection)
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], December 31, 1802; B J35.83; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Tho[ma]s Jefferson to the Miami and Delaware Indians., January 8, 1803; B J35.82; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    MSL-1 [Washington], 4 pp. Copy of D.S. FILM199 FRAME428
  - Letter to Mrs. Eppes, Jan. 18, 1803; B J35.34; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Her arrival at Edgehill. Mr. Giles's aid in Congress.
  - Recognition of Alire Raffeneau De Lille [sic] as sub-commissionary of commercial relations with France, Oct. 20, 1803; B J35.50; 15-1/2x10; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Photostat of D.S.: Th.Jefferson, pres. and James Madison, Sec. of state. 1p. Presented by W.J.Robbins.
  - Letter to Dugald Stewart, December 21,1803; B J35.84; Buchan, David Stewart Erskine, Earl of, 1742-1829
    S. Castle street, Photostat of A.N.S. 1p. and enc. - 2p. Encloses copy of letter from president Jefferson [Jefferson to Buchan, July 10, 1803]. From original in Laing collection, University of Edinburgh.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, January 4, 1805; B J35.68; 10x8; James, Thomas C., (Thomas Chalkley), 1766-1835
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Informs Jefferson of his reelection as president of the A.P.S.
  - Commission to Meriwether Lewis, April 15, 1805; B J35.55; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Photo.of printed D.filled in in ms.S. 1p. (from photograph,not original document). Presented by Mrs. Robbins; May 1962.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, April 27, 1805; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 8"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Copy of L. 1p. and add. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson,1805-1824) Offers him the office of Director of the Mint. Bur. of Rolls S.1,10,289.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, June 13, 1805; B J35.p; 10" x 8"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., add. and end. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson,1805-1824) Mr. Patterson will receive commission as Director of the Mint as Mr. Boudinot's resignation takes effect the last day of the month. Bur. of rolls. S.2,67,65.
  - Letter to Messrs. McDowell, Rodger, Finley, and Patterson, Aug. 31, 1805; B J35.3; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, sends a small parcel of the Jerusalem wheat which he received from a gentleman in Ireland. Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. and add. Copy (?) in Mass. hist. soc.
  - Letter to [Samuel Latham] Mitchell (sic), Sept. 8, 1805; B J35.16; 7 3/4" x 8 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L. in 3d P. 1p. On his return to Washington, expects to find a collection of the chemical subjects of Louisiana which Capt. Lewis desires forwarded to the Philosophical society at Philadelphia. Bureau of rolls,v.6,p.327 - S.2, v.60,no.113.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, July, 1805; B J35.61; 8x6-1/4; Marum, M. van (Martinus), 1750-1837
    Ha[a]rlem, Photo.of L. 1p. In French. (from original in Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen, Haarlem.) Notifies him of election to "Societe Batavé". Refers to the APS.
  - Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824; B J35.p; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    13 items in 12 - all A.L.S.'s but 1. 27 April, 13 June 1805. 5 Nov 1806. 18 Oct 1807. 21 March 1811. 29 May, 9 Aug. 1812. 13 Oct 22, Dec 1815. 18 Oct. 1818. 2 Feb, 4 July 1819. 17 May 1824. With this collection came a letter from J. Madison to Patterson. July 2, 1805. (see in Misc. mss. collections)
  - Letter to Destutt-Tracy, Feb. 14, 1806; B J35.75; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his work on Ideologie; favorable comments on it. De Tracy elected to the APS.
  - Letter to M[artin] Van Marum, Ha[a]rlem, May 3, 1806; B J35.60; 10x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and add. (from original in Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen, Haarlem.) Thanks for election to the Batavian society and will be "a willing intermediate [sic]" for relations with the APS.
  - Letter to [Francois Andre] Michaux, July 12, 1806; B J35.71; 11x7; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Copy of A.L. in 3rd P. 1p. (From Charles Hamilton Auction No. 73, Dec. 6, 1973.) Thanks Michaux for "the book of his travels & the pamphlet he has been so kind as to send him."
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Nov. 5, 1806; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see T. Jefferson to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Acknowledges receipt of the Nautical almanac and two small tracts. Bur. of rolls S.2,67,68
  - Drawing of a carriage, with manuscript notes, 1806; B J35.29; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    ca. Photostat of A.D. 3p.,accompanied by photostats of letter, in another hand, in German, dated: Jan.15, 1806. (from the original in the University of Virginia.)
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Oct. 18, 1807; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Sends some Arabic notes relative to two persons confined on suspicion; asks aid in translating in order to release the men if proper. Bur. of rolls, S.2,67,70.
  - Letter to [James]? Cheetham, Nov. 6, 1807; B J35.76; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. Concerns payment of newspaper bill. Syas he is nearing retirement and has not read N.Y. Evening Post for two years. Don't send any more.
  - Letter to Samuel H. Smith, Dec. 16, 1807; B J35.25; 7" x 9"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and add., end. Contains note by S.H. Smith (?) Questions whether enclosed pieces are worth publishing [ca. British merchants].
  - Letter to Henry Voigt, Philadelphia, Jan. 6, 1808; B J35.65; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Sends money for watch and hopes it can be delivered by a person who will carry it in his pocket; suggests Jonathan Williams.
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams, Jan. 19, 1808; B J35.31; 8" x 5"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and add. Excuses himself from attending meeting [of the U.S. Military philosophical society].
  - Letter to [Thomas] Jefferson, Jan. 21, 1808; B J35.x11; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Williams, Jonathan, 1750-1815
    Washington, A.Dr. of L. 2p., end. Encloses letter from Gov. Franklin to his son, W.T.Franklin; dissension between them. Delay in W.T.F.'s publication of his grandfather's papers; suggests that APS demand some action.
  - Letter to C. W. Peale; Passport for Rembrandt Peale, March 13, 1808; B J35.18; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and enc. - 1p. Seal on enc. Encloses a passport for his son, Rembrandt Peale, who goes abroad to paint portraits; suggests eleven Frenchmen who might sit for him. Reproduced: APS Library Bulletin for 1946, p.12.
  - Letter to M[arquis] de la Fayette, July 18, 1808; B J35.77; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. Mentions Duplantier. Concerns the negotiation of lands and the sale to the city of New Orleans.
  - Memorial to James Madison concerning his ship of slaves which was captured and sold in Cuba, July 28, 1808; B J35.57; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Grove, S. (Samuel), 1782-1834
    Charleston, D.S. 1p.and end.by T.Jefferson with a statement on U.S.policy on slavery. Presented by Morris Duane; Nov. 26, 1963.
  - Memorial to James Madison, Aug. 17, 1808; B J35.57; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Grove, S. (Samuel), 1782-1834
    asking that his ship of slaves be recaptured for him, and a note by Th[omas] Jefferson, as president, that "The government of the U.S. will not make itself an accomplice in...selling them in slavery. Charleston, July 28, 1808. D.S. 1p.and end. (see Jefferson papers.) Presented by Morris Duane,Nov.1963.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], January 6, 1809; B J35.69; 10-1/2x8-3/4; James, Thomas C., (Thomas Chalkley), 1766-1835
  - Letters patent for plot of ground in the territory northwest of the Ohio, Steubenville, issued to William Crawford, Feb. 10, 1809; B J35.49; 8 1/2" x 15 1/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, D.C., Printed D. filled in and S: Th. Jefferson, president; James Madison, secretary of state. 1p. Seal.
  - [Plan for an agricultural society; ?], March, 1811; B J35.19; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.D. 4p. Printed: Lipscomb and Bergh,v.17,404.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, March 21, 1811; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 8"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson,1805-1824). His interest in astronomy and scientific instruments. Bur. of rolls S.2,67,58.
  - Letter to ---- Goodman, Oct. 10(?), 1812; B J35.4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, relates to the finishing of a certain house. Photostat of A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, May 29, 1812; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson,1805-1824) Sends papers intended for the [American philosophical] Society. Necessity for uniformity in a system of weights and measures. Bur. of rolls, S.2,67,59
  - Letter to [Robert] Patterson, Aug. 9, 1812; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Sends paper by William Lambert and recommends him for membership in the APS. War with Great Britain.
  - Letter to Paul Allen, Aug.18, 1813; B J35.40; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photostat of A.L.S. 14p. Biographical information in re Meriwether Lewis; instructions for the Lewis and Clark expedition. Sponsorship by APS of earlier expedition of André Michaux. Printed: Lewis and Clark, History of expedition, by Paul Allen, Phila., 1814, v.1,vii. Presented by Mr. Charles Biddle from draft in L.C., Feb. 1954.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, June 29, 1813; B J35.x15; 10 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Fulton, Robert, 1765-1815
    New York, A.Dr. of L.S. 15p. and end. illus. Describes experiments for firing projectiles under water. With this is Fulton's: Specification of my mode of firing under water and destroying ships of war,1813. 8p. 9 3/4" x 8" The handwriting of the two documents is authenticated by George H. Moore and R.H. Thurston.
  - Letter to Thomas Voigt, Philadelphia, July 30, 1813; B J35.66; 10x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Orders a lady's watch and specifies how to pack it for shipment. Mr. Short will advise on chain needed.
  - Letter to James Madison, Washington, Feb. 14, 1814; B J35.5; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Forwards letter from Mr. Mill.
  - Letter to Joseph Nicholson, May 21, 1814; B J35.26; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Comments on his cooperation in "atchieving... the republican ascendancy and rescuing our constitution from... those who were...monarchising it." Mentions Mr. McCulloch.
  - Letter to Th. Jefferson,Monticello, June 10, 1814; B J35.x14; 13 3/4" x 8"; Leavitt, Dudley, 1772-1851
    Centre Harbor, N.H., A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Transcribes a lunar table which he asks to be laid before the APS. (Enclosed originally with letter from T. Jefferson to Robert Patterson, June 29, 1814, which see) Presented by the Rev. James O. Patterson, Aug. 1955. Not found: 7/19/2010
  - Letter to Robert Patterson,Phila., June 29, 1814; B J35.47; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Asks that he forward the enclosed paper to the Philosophical Society (Dudley Leavit to T. Jefferson, June 10, 1814 - which see) Presented by the Rev. James O. Patterson, Aug. 1955.
  - Letter to Dr. William Thornton, Feb. 9, 1815; B J35.30; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Contains short note by Dr. Thornton. Water supply for Monticello. Crosbie's claim to Janes' loom. Small portion printed: Betts' Jefferson's garden book,p. 541.
  - Letter to R[obert] Patterson, Oct. 13, 1815; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and portion of add. leaf Reverse contains draft (inc.) of Patterson's reply, Nov.22,1815. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Instructions for shipping the time piece. Comments on scientific instruments.
  - Letter to James Maese (sic), Phila., Oct. 15, 1815; B J35.37; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Information about American medals; mentions Dr. Franklin. Bur. of Rolls. Ser.2,v.61,no.26.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Dec. 22, 1815; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Wrote to the President on behalf of Mr. Hassler. Scientific instruments.
  - Letter to Matthew Carey, Oct. [Nov. ?] 11, 1816; B J35.20; 6 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Poplar Forest near Lynchburg, A.L. 1p. and add. (signature cut off, another supplied) Carey's Olive Branch. Rejection of British treaty without laying it before the Senate. Views on religion. Bur. of rolls, v.6,65 - Ser. 1,v.14, 101
  - Letter to J.W. Eppes, April 30, 1816; B J35.44; 10" x 8"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p. Education of Francis [Eppes]. Prophecy of great intercourse with Spanish America.
  - Letter to John W. Eppes, March 6, 1817; B J35.43; 9 3/4" x 8", 2 1/2" x 5"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p. and scrap of address Sends dial and various shrubs, including cuttings of a snowberry bush and the sweet scented curran[t] which were brought from the Pacific ocean by Lewis and Clark.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Sept. 16, 1817; B J35.x16; 8-1/2x6-3/4; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Jefferson papers.) His difficulties at UofP. Proposal for removing to Williamsburg on certain conditions, to teach medicine there.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 18, 1818; B J35; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    dated Monticello, mentions the death of Dr. [Caspar] Wistar; thinks the continuation of Wistar's weekly assemblages worthy of Mr. Vaughan's attention. A.L.S. 1p. Endorsement on back in Vaughan's (?) hand: 1818 - Jefferson on Death of Wistar; also in another hand: Thomas Jefferson to Jno Vaughan, Monticello, Purchased in February 1938 from Arthur Pforzheimer, 26 E. 56th St., New York City for $54.
  - Letter to [Mordecai Noah], Montecello, Repro., 28 May, 1818; B J35.79; 8 1/2 x 11; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    of ALS. 1p. On Judaism, prejudice, public opinion, and religious freedom. From Sotheby's Preview #66, 1986.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 6, 1818; B J35.48; 9 3/4" x 8"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1824
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Returns letter for Mr. Correa, as he and Dr. Cooper have set out for Philadelphia. Asks for further explanation in re instruments for the Astronomical committee and the danger of losing the privilege of the building [of the APS ?]. Presented by Mrs. Howard W. Lang, December 1955.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Oct. 18, 1818; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. "Copy" 1p. Transcribed on obverse of letter of Feb.2, 1819. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Sends telescope in care of Mr. Trist to be repaired in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Feb. 2, 1819; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. One same sheet with letter of Oct. 18,1818 (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Transcribes copy of letter of Oct. 18, 1818 in re repair of telescope.
  - Letter to [Joseph-Leonard] Poirey, March 8, 1819; B J35.78; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. Concerns payment for services. Recounts delays in getting the act of Congress authorizing payment. Mentions Lafayette.
  - Letter to M. [John] Lavel, June 4, 1819; B J35.22; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to a volume of Grimm.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, July 4, 1819; B J35.p; 10" x 8"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and add. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Sends letter and remittance to Mr. Davenport.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, Feb. 3, 1823; B J35.x19; 12-1/2x8-1/2; Fabbroni, Leopoldo Pelli
    Florence, Italy, L. 2p. In French. Draft. (see Jefferson Papers.) Death of his father, Giovanni Fabroni.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, April 10, 1824; B J35.38; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Relative to appointment as professor at the University [of Virginia].
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, May 17, 1824; B J35.39; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges volume of chemistry; comments on its applications to the utilities of life; makes favorable comparison with discoveries of illustrious ancestor [B. Franklin]. Draft of letter in L.C.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, May 17, 1824; B J35.p; 9 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see T. Jefferson. Letters to Robert Patterson, 1805-1824) Enclosed letter and pamphlet from the Baron de Ferrusac to be referred to the APS.
  - Letter to Mr. [Thomas] Jefferson, May 30, 1824; B J35.x13; 9 3/4" x 8"; Brown, Samuel, 1769-1830
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Recommends Dr. [Franklin] Bache for the chair of Chemistry at the University of Virginia.
  - Letter to [David] Shriver, dated, Dec. 21, 1824; B J35.2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    acknowledges receipt of pamphlet and map on the canal uniting the eastern and western waters. A.L. in 3d P. 1p. 0. Photostat. Original in possession of Henry Shriver. Presented by J. Alexis Shriver, see accompanying letter for further details.
  - Letter to the Rev. Mr. Hatch, March 16, 1825; B J35.17; 8" x 4 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.N. in 3d P. 1p. and add. Relative to the course of study for his grandsons, Benjamin and Lewis.
  - Catalogue of engraved portraits of Thomas Jefferson..., 1889; B J35ca; 6 1/2 x 4; Campbell, William J., -1931
    2 vols. 3 ms. vols. ca.500p. Includes also one vol. "Points of Interest about Portraits of Thomas Jefferson." 1. Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826. I. Assoc.: Campbell, William J. II. Assoc.: Campbell, William M.
  - Commonplace book, March 20, 1943; B J35.g; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Typescript. 284p.and covering letter: G. Chinard to R.S. Morris; Unpublished part of: Chinard, ed. T. Jefferson. Commonplace book... Presented by R.S. Morris, as suggested in above letter, by G. Chinard; 1944.
  - [List of slaves at Poplar Forest and Bear Creek, giving clothing and blankets needed], Undated; B J35.27; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.D. 4p. Not found: 7/19/2010
  - [Commonplace book], Undated; B J35.cL; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Photostat of A.D. pp.1-114, 137 [i.e. 228p.] F. From original in Library of Congress. Presented by Dr. Gilbert Chinard, 1946. Unlocated. See Subject File.
  - ...Farm book...ed. by Edwin M. Betts., Undated; B J35.f; 11" x 8 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Typescript 1381p. Original ms. of volume prepared by Dr. Betts and published as Vol. 35. of APS Memoirs. Presented by Dr. Betts, June 1954.
  - Letter to Mr. Rittenhouse, Undated; B J35.28; 7 3/4" x 5"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monday morng. A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and add. Sends certain books; asks for return of others.